<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Azirona Blog</title>
    <link>https://azirona.com/</link>
    <description>hi there</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well why doesn&apos;t a governmental authority control and delegate who has access to the data center? Wo</title>
      <description>Well why doesn&apos;t a governmental authority control and delegate who has access to the data center? Wouldn&apos;t that be better than letting the public go all Wild West on it and demand more, more, more? You want a government agency to step in and regulate what we can and can&apos;t see, what data we can and can&apos;t use, how much data we can and can&apos;t process: good freaking luck, my man. That&apos;ll piss off way more than the ever-edgy libertarians and anarcho-capitalist twin cousins.
So this development is likely inevitable. And I even see the potential for great good to come of it. Although I&apos;m not planning on that one bit. There is one ray of sunshine to this, however: local communities are banding together on this issue. I may ultimately disagree with them on this issue (I&apos;m too jaded to decide right now); I&apos;m just really glad to see small towns light their beacons and rally their populaces, getting the word out and sounding alarm bells to at least pay attention.
The local level is the one I care most about. The rest of the country is &quot;not in my backyard.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:45:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-21</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Stories of data centers getting constructed in towns across the US have come out over the past year.</title>
      <description>Stories of data centers getting constructed in towns across the US have come out over the past year. One is finally slated for our area, a local friend tipped all of their friends and I happened to see the post. Didn&apos;t think I&apos;d ever deal with this, then realized some alarming conclusions, so I&apos;m diving deeper.
Just YouTube alone has grown to the point where its digital data growth is over 4 petabytes per day. If you have a 1TB hard drive, get 4,000 more, and you have YouTube&apos;s daily growth. Actually a lot smaller than I imagined. Of course, that&apos;s just YouTube, one site out of billions. All the data generated in a day gets stored somewhere. That storage has to be present somewhere. Where is our Gmail account data stored? Somewhere, surely.
I never heard debate of these data centers until the past 12 months. What&apos;s the difference? Seems to be AI (as it ever is and will be for the foreseeable future). Machine learning is something I heard about in the late 2010s to great hype. &quot;Big data&quot; was something to put on your resume. Just the initial applications for machine learning of &quot;big data&quot; showed promise, in my opinion. Lot of industries could use that kind of processing power. And think of the future: going to outer space, these applications and their complications will have to grow ...astronomically.
Remember the crypto craze? Alarming reports went out about crypto mining operations, ostensibly placed in colder climate countries to reduce costs on keeping the electronics from overheating. Consuming vast amounts of electricity has been on the minds of environmentally-minded people for an entire century. The NIMBY-ism was there too, it&apos;s just scaled up.
&quot;NIMBY&quot; stands for &quot;not in my backyard.&quot; Nobody wants a multi-acre, noisy, water-guzzling, energy-consuming, polluting data center across the street from them. Do I want that in my small town? No. Short and selfish answer is &quot;No.&quot; It&apos;s the natural human reaction.
But I can be sold on it. My price doesn&apos;t come cheap. I need to know exactly how this is going to be used. Who has access to it. What types of data are getting processed. What sort of environmental remediation treatments are promised. How those remediation treatments would be verified. Why all this? I can see industries and hospitals utilizing these data centers to boost production, cut costs, reduce wait times for patient care, increasing effectiveness, contributing to research.
Bunch of our metals come from the ground. IN the ground. That ground is rock and has to be processed if we&apos;re going to get the metals out of it. The ground isn&apos;t moving: we have to accept that. If you sit on a vein of gold or a trap of oil in your backyard, you&apos;d think twice before rushing to refuse construction on your property. Point is you should think twice, regardless of which direction you initially want to rush off towards.
Rare Earth Elements (REEs) are a key export from overseas (China). The process for retrieving and refining them is inhumane, or exorbitant. Look up some photos of the villagers deformed by living near the operations. Oh we would never support that... Every lithium battery does. Every solar cell does. From electric vehicles to rooftop solar panels, our dollars contribute to that inhumane process.
AI data centers could be used to invent new technologies, improve current ones, cut down on inefficiencies, free up labor for other tasks. If that&apos;s what happens, we could be looking at a huge increase in productivity, life longevity, medicine availability, industrial progress, and overall knowledge base.
My pessimism says otherwise. AI data centers will be used instead to flood social media with fake news, escape further from reality through games and virtual companions. That isn&apos;t the AI&apos;s fault, however. It&apos;s not the data center&apos;s fault either. That&apos;s our fault. Collectively, we&apos;re &quot;dun goofing&quot; right now. Smart phones carried this possibility too, the world&apos;s knowledge and a million useful applications in the palm of our hands. We don&apos;t use it for that and we know it.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:45:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-20</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>#webpub

Early

I&apos;m really, REALLY bad about getting up early in the morning. At heart, I am a morni</title>
      <description>#webpub

Early

I&apos;m really, REALLY bad about getting up early in the morning. At heart, I am a morning person, but I consciously prefer acting like a night owl.
&quot;Early&quot; applies to much more beyond the time we get up. This year, our household has the opportunity to file our taxes ridiculously early. Most years haven&apos;t been this easy; there were pre-tax investments, after-tax investments, small business incomes, small business expenditures, investment withdrawals, and occupation changing. Not this year. This year, it&apos;s just my income. Should be simple.
To be able to resolve our tax return before February would actually be faster than I&apos;ve ever heard out of anyone. Would be a huge load of worry off our mind. Politics of the federal income tax aside, it&apos;d be nice to just not have to think about it till next year.
Starting this early means preparing for potential complications. Does the IRS take issue with our tax return? We have time to resolve that. Miss a source of income we previously thought invalid? We can incorporate that before April 15th. Good ol&apos; fashioned issues with the US Postal Service? We can wait.
Every year we wait until early April, it&apos;s just worse. Better to just get it out of the way.
This applies most other places in life. Investing from an earlier age invariably leads to bigger returns. Physical exercise done earlier always leads to an easier time getting back into shape later on. Doing something right the first time is better than attempting to do it over.
I can hear exceptions brewing in some of your heads. Of course there are exceptional circumstances. I&apos;m not dealing with them.
Make a point to do work, hard work, the annoying work, first. Get that out of your day&apos;s way. You will thank yourself later.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 13:22:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-19</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>*The Cheese*

October 9, 2025
by Juleah Miller
#webpub

The boy trailed several feet behind his moth</title>
      <description>*The Cheese*

October 9, 2025
by Juleah Miller
#webpub

The boy trailed several feet behind his mother, stepping carefully over the cracks and only in the pale blue, dingy vinyl tiles. He found himself here among the towering, poorly organized shelves quite reluctantly, it being too hot in the middle of summer to hang out in the car. He could feel his mother&apos;s tension at the thought of having to police a toddler and hastily shop for groceries on a limited time budget. This divided attention lent well to his curious little hands and the myriad of brightly colored packages; the boxes recieving a light rebuke from mother, and glass jars invoking the full wrath of God. The scathing corrections slid right over the toddler&apos;s immature brain like water off a ducks back.

Low rumbles, quiet chatter, intermittent beeps, and an inoffensive jingle mixed into a slurry of sounds assaulting and drowning the senses of the boy. The low cacophany ceased in a moment and the lights dimmed, casting the boy into deep shadow. For a moment, he paused, searching for the cause of the sudden absence of all senses. The boy&apos;s mother continued her harried shopping, her muttering and shuffling a dull note amongst the nothing.

The boy slowly became aware of the glow beyond his mother. The light grew in intensity until his mother was a mere silhouette, her shadow shrinking in the blinding light. The boy&apos;s feet stumbled forward, drawn hypnotically by the light. Eyes never leaving, he stepped around his mother. The light hit his eyes with full intensity. Instictively, his hands flew up to cover his face. Eyes watering, the glow abated as his eyes adjusted to the light. A cold blast of air chilled his cheeks. Upon the shelves, mist swirling, sat a glorious block of cheese. It was pure gold, and the smell... the smell. The boy had never smelled anything more delicious. Before he properly registered it, the cheese rested reverently in his hands. Arms cradling it as if it were a newborn fawn. The cheese was simultaneously cool and vibrantly warm.

Claws sharply clutched his shoulder and the illusion broke. The rumble, beeps, chatter, and lights flooded back to his senses; the cheese ripped from his hands as quickly as his fingers found it. The scold was harsh.The words washed over his body as he watched the cheese blasphemed, merely tossed irreverantly back onto the shelf. Tears stung the boys eyes, not at the verbal barbs from his mother, but for the callous disregard for his perfect cheese.

The tongue lashing and finger wagging finished quickly, the mother remembering how little time she truly had for this excursion. The boy stood still, shocked and rooted to the spot. His mother turned away with an impatient beckoning of her hand. Head frozen, the boy&apos;s eyes slid until his gaze fell upon the cheese once more. The radiant warmth of its embrace welcomed him. His eyes slid to his mother now several feet away and counting. The timing would soon close before she turned and griped at him again.

The boy&apos;s brain didn&apos;t process the movement, but he found himself walking dutifully behind his mother, cheese in hand. The boxes and jars no longer called to him, their color dulled and ugly before the brilliant glow of the golden cheese. He gave no cause for his mother to look down. Her mood considerably brightened and the shopping experienced streamlined, the hedge maze of shelves blurring together. Nothing else was real. He had his cheese.

Beep, beep, beep. The hand of the cashier deftly scanned another item from the pile of boxes and bags bumping along the wet conveyor belt. The boy&apos;s mother breathed a sigh of relief. The boy clutched the cheese, leaning as if glued to his mother&apos;s leg. Money exchanged hands. The bags crinkled in his mother&apos;s grip. She stepped away from the register and sighed with a smile. Her eyes took one last look around the area, searching for anything amiss. Her eyes fell on the boy.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-17</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Darkness plunged around the boy once more. His cheese glowed dimmly in his arms, barely illuminating</title>
      <description>Darkness plunged around the boy once more. His cheese glowed dimmly in his arms, barely illuminating his mother standing just beyond the golden halo. A sharp whistling from afar rushed in and penetrated his ears. The boy&apos;s mothering leaned into his circle of light, her face lit from below, holding a peculiar blank expression that he had never seen before. His mother snaked her arm slowly around his middle. The boy froze. The whistling reached an earshattering pitch. Sound, darkness, and his world imploded at same time she constricted his waist.

The boy lifted high into the air, his cheese ripped from his hands by claws like razorblades. The beep, beep, beep carried on.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 22:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-18</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Channel photo updated</title>
      <description>Channel photo updated</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 03:23:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-2</guid>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Channel created</title>
      <description>Channel created</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 03:19:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>telegram-post-1</guid>
    </item>
  
  </channel>
</rss>